Guide to the Emil Schwarzhaupt Foundation Papers 1945-1987
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: Administrative Records
  - Subseries 2: University of Chicago Committee on Education for American Citizenship; Recommendations
    - "Recommendations to the Trustees of the Emil Schwarzhaupt Foundation," April 27, 1953; "Notes in Regard to the Emil Schwarzhaupt Foundation," remarks by Carl Tjerandsen, April 1, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 3: Minutes and Financial Reports
    - 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1974-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1975-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4: Financial Statements and Tax Returns
    - Receipt and release of Estate of Leonard Gerngross, January 28, 1959; "Survey of Scientific Activities of Nonprofit Institutions During 1964; Private Philanthropic Foundations," January 10, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Financial Statements, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Financial Statements, December 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Financial Statements, October 1971-December 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Financial Statements, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 5: Correspondence
    - November 1952-June 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - July 1953-October 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - November 1953-April 1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - June 1954-October 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - November 1954-July 1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - July 1955-August 1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - September 1955-June 1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - July 1956-May 1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - June 1957-December 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - June 1953-December 1954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - January 1955-ca. 1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 6: Activity Reports of Carl Tjerandsen to the Foundation Trustees
    - Account of days/time worked, 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 7: Grant Application Recommendations
    - Active Citizens Opinion Poll-Bates College (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Carrie Chapman Catt Memorial Fund-Constitution and Free Enterprise Foundation (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Encampment for Citizenship-Hyde Park-Kenwood Community Conference (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Institute of International Education-North Kenwood-Oakland Community Conference (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Patriotic Education, Inc.-Young Adult Council of the National Social Welfare Assembly (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Recommendations appraising more than one application (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 8: Evaluation Report of Highlander Folk School and Industrial Areas Foundation
    - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Comments by Septima Clark, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Draft, field, and census data notes used by J. Herman Blake (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "Citizen Participation, Democracy, and Social Change; A Report to the Emil Schwarzhaupt Foundation" (September 1, 1968), by J. Herman Blake, preliminary report (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "Citizen Participation, Democracy and Social Change," final report (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 9: Schwarzhaupt Foundation; Final Report
    - Carl Tjerandsen, Education for Citizenship; A Foundation's Experience (Santa Cruz, CA.; Emil Schwarzhaupt Foundation, 1980), published copy (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, March-September 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, October-November 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, December 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, January-May 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, August-October 1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, November-December 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, January 11-17, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, January 18-28, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, March-July 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, August 1980-January 1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Handwritten notes and outlines (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - Typewritten drafts, notes, and chapter material (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
    - News clippings (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 10: American Indian Background Material Gathered by Carl Tjerandsen
    - Tjerandsen's notes, n.d.; correspondence, 1953-1971; article reprints (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Handouts and news clippings (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Series II: Application for Funds and Grants
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Applications and recommendations, 1954-1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Correspondence, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Correspondence, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Correspondence, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Correspondence, 1962-1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Reports, June 14, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Reports, ca. 1951 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, November, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, March 1953; October 1953 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, April 27, 1954 (with memorandum) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, March 18, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, April 11, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, March 31, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, March 31, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, March 31, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, April 20, 1960 (with correspondence) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Reports, 1961-1964, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Reports, 1967-1972 (Five Year Report) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Report, April 1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Reports, 1971-1972 (Brief Annual Report); April 1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., "One Year Report on Refugees from the Soviet Union, August 1, 1972 to July 31, 1973" (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., April 1974; "Statement on Soviet Refugees" (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - American Council for Emigres in the Professions, Inc., Annual Report, May 1975-April 1976 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Applications and recommendations, March 1953-March 1954 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Applications and recommendations, April-December 1954 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Applications and recommendations, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Applications and recommendations, May 1956-May 7, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Applications and recommendations, May 15, 1957-May 1, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, February-September 1953 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, October 1953-January 1954 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, February-May 1954 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, June-October 1954 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, November 1954-March 1955 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, April-August 1955 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, September-December 1955 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, January-May 1956 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, July-October 1956 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, November 1956-March 1957 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, April-June 1957 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, July-December 1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, March-July 1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, August 1958-January 1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Correspondence, April 1959-January 1968 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Reports, 1951-1959 (Box 10, Folder 5-8)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Newsletters, 1951-1957 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - American Indian Center, Chicago, Applications and recommendations, 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - American Indian Center, Chicago, Correspondence, 1954-1958 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - American Indian Center, Chicago, Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - American Indian Center, Chicago, Correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - American Indian Center, Chicago, Financial reports, 1959-1970 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - American Indian Center, Chicago, Reports, 1954-1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - American Indian Center, Chicago, Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - American Indian Center, Chicago, Newsletter, Chicago Warrior, November 1957-July 1968; programs and newspaper clippings (Box 11, Folder 3-7)
  - American Indian Development, Applications and recommendations, 1954-January 1955 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - American Indian Development, Applications and recommendations, March 1955 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - American Indian Development, Applications and recommendations, April 1955-November 1957 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - American Indian Development, Applications and recommendations, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - American Indian Development, Applications and recommendations, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, January 1954-May 1955 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, July-September 13, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, September 22, 1955-April 1956 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, May 1956-June 1957 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, July-December 1957 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, January 1960-May 15, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - American Indian Development, Correspondence, May 23, 1963-March 1967 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - American Indian Development, Reports, 1952-1956 (Box 12, Folder 10-14)
  - American Indian Development, Reports, 1957-1959, 1963 (outline of materials for final report) (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
  - American Indian Development, D'Arcy McNickle and Viola G. Pfrommer, "Dinetxa; A Community Experience," September 1964 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - American Indian Development, Navajo Development Committee, minutes, (includes remarks of participants) 1955-1959 (Box 13, Folder 7-13)
  - American Indian Development, Unsigned petitions and news clippings (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Applications and recommendations, ca. 1956-1957 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Correspondence, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Correspondence, January-April 1957 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Correspondence, April 17, 1957-August 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Reports, 1956-1961 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), By-laws and news clippings, 1956-1973 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Applications and recommendations, 1959-1960 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Correspondence, 1961-ca. 1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Reports (on summer workshops), 1956-1960 (Box 14, Folder 10-13)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Rosalie H. Wax, "A Brief History and Analysis of the Workshops on American Indian Affairs, 1956-1960," October 1961 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Reports, 1964-1966 (Box 14, Folder 15-17)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Newsletters and pamphlets, 1959-1967 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Government grant applications and resumes (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Arrow, Inc. (Pine Ridge, SD Reservation), Student statements from the 1961 workshop (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Benton House, Chicago, Applications and recommendations, reports, 1956-1959 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Benton House, Chicago, Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Benton House, Chicago, Correspondence, 1958-1961 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Benton House, Chicago, Ruth F. Fennessey and Ignacia Torres, "Four Years of Progress; The Aims, Methods, and Results of the Program under the Schwarzhaupt Foundation Grant," July 1961 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Better Housing League of Cincinnati, Applications and recommendations, 1954-1960 (with statement of tax exemption) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Better Housing League of Cincinnati, Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Better Housing League of Cincinnati, Reports, 1956-1962 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Better Housing League of Cincinnati, Final report (charts and graphs), 1962 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Board of Urban Ministry (Rochester, NY), Applications and recommendations, correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Board of Urban Ministry (Rochester, NY), Newsletters, 1958-1966 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Board of Urban Ministry (Rochester, NY), Pamphlets and news clippings (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Catholic Interracial Council of Chicago, Applications and recommendations, 1956-1959 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Catholic Interracial Council of Chicago, Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Catholic Interracial Council of Chicago, Financial report and supplemental information, 1957-1958 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Catholic Interracial Council of Chicago, Newsletters, pamphlets, and news clippings, 1955-1959 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Commons Association, Applications and recommendations, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Chicago Commons Association, Correspondence, 1957-1962; financial report, August 31, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Chicago Commons Association, Myrtle Chamberlin, "Report to the Emil Schwarzhaupt Foundation," September 6, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Chicago Commons Association, Announcements (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Church Federation of Greater Chicago, Applications and recommendations, correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Citizen Information Service of Metropolitan Chicago, Applications and recommendations, 1954-1958 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Citizen Information Service of Metropolitan Chicago, Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Citizen Information Service of Metropolitan Chicago, Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Citizen Information Service of Metropolitan Chicago, Reports, 1957-1960 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
  - Citizen Information Service of Metropolitan Chicago, Supplemental information (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Citizen Information Service of Metropolitan Chicago, Newsletters and news clippings (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Citizen Planning and Housing Association, Applications and recommendations, 1956-1959 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Citizen Planning and Housing Association, Correspondence, 1957-1962 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Citizen Planning and Housing Association, Reports, 1956-1962 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Citizen Planning and Housing Association, Newsletters and news clippings (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Citizen Planning and Housing Association, Pamphlets and article reprints (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Citizenship Clearing House, Applications and recommendations, 1954-1956 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Citizenship Clearing House, Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Citizenship Clearing House, Report (summer workshop), 1953 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Citizenship Clearing House, "A Report to the Board of Trustees of the Emil Schwarzhaupt Foundation on the Activities of the Citizenship Clearing House," November 1, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Citizenship Clearing House, Newsletter, Citizenship Clearing House Bulletin, 1952-1962 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Citizenship Clearing House, Publications and news clippings (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
  - Colony House, Brooklyn, Applications and recommendations, correspondence, 1957-1962 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Colony House, Brooklyn, Reports and news clippings, 1957-1962 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Colony House, Brooklyn, Financial reports, 1958-1962 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Columbia University, Legislative Drafting Research Fund, Applications and recommendations, correspondence, and news clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Community Service Organization, Fresno, Applications and recommendations, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Earlham College, Applications and recommendations, speech by William Biddle, 1956-1960 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Earlham College, Correspondence, April 1956-June 1957 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Earlham College, Correspondence, July 1957-August 1963 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Earlham College, Loureide J. Biddle and William W. Biddle, Community Dynamic Processes, draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Earlham College, Loureide J. Biddle and William W. Biddle, Community Dynamic Processes; Two Community Case Studies of People in Development, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Earlham College, Newsletter, Community Development Bulletin, 1964-1966 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Earlham College, Reports, 1948-1960 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Applications and recommendations, 1953-1961 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Correspondence, July 1950-1954 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Correspondence, July 1954-July 1956 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Correspondence, October 1956-December 1958 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Correspondence, 1961-1981 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Reports, 1950-1970 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Newsletter, Summer Projects, and news clippings, 1956-1974 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Pamphlets and promotional information (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Herbert H. Hyman and Charles R. Wright, "Youth in Transition; An Evaluation of the Contribution of the Encampment for Citizenship" (March 1962) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Algernon D. Black, The Young Citizens; The Story of the Encampment for Citizenship (New York; Frederick Ungar Publishing Co., 1962) (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, Herbert H. Hyman, Charles R. Wright, and Terence K. Hopkins, Applications of methods of Evaluation; Four Studies of the Encampment for American Citizenship (Berkeley; University of California Press, 1962) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Fellowship House of Cincinnati, Applications and recommendations, correspondence, 1954-1959 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Fellowship House of Cincinnati, Reports, 1956-1959 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Fellowship House of Cincinnati, Pamphlets and promotional literature (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Fellowship House of Philadelphia, Applications and recommendations, 1953-1959 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Fellowship House of Philadelphia, Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Fellowship House of Philadelphia, Correspondence, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Fellowship House of Philadelphia, Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Fellowship House of Philadelphia, Correspondence, 1957-1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Fellowship House of Philadelphia, Reports and survey handbook, 1950-1959 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Fellowship House of Philadelphia, Newsletters, pamphlets and news clippings (Box 20, Folder 10-11)
  - Freedom House, Boston, Applications and recommendations, reports, 1957-1963 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Freedom House, Boston, Correspondence, 1956-1963 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Freedom House, Boston, Newsletters, pamphlets and news clippings (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, Inc., Applications and recommendations, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, Inc., Report and request, 1957; "Report to the Schwarzhaupt Foundation," 1958 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, Inc., Correspondence, 1953-1957 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, Inc., Correspondence, 1958-1982 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, Inc., Reports to Congress, 1954-1981 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, Inc., Supplemental reports, 1956-1959 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, Inc., Reports, newsletters and pamphlets, 1955-1966 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Goddard College, Applications and recommendations, 1957, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Goddard College, Correspondence, 1951-1962 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Goddard College, Alan M. Walker, "Vermont Community Development Program; Final Report to the Emil Schwarzhaupt Foundation," October 1, 1962; reports, 1959-1964 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Highlander Folk School, Applications and recommendations, 1956-1981 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Highlander Folk School, Correspondence, 1973-1982 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Highlander Folk School, Newsletters, 1948-1987 (Box 22, Folder 13-14)